{
  "Java": [
    {
      "Rookie": [
        {
          "question": "Which one of these lists contains only Java programming language keywords?",
          "opt1": "class, if, void, long",
          "opt2": "goto, instanceof, native, throws",
          "opt3": "try, virtual, throw, final",
          "opt4": "strictfp, constant, super, do",
          "ans": "goto, instanceof, native, throws"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which is a reserved word in the Java programming language?",
          "opt1": "method",
          "opt2": "native",
          "opt3": "subclasses",
          "opt4": "reference",
          "ans": "native"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which is a valid keyword in java?",
          "opt1": "interface",
          "opt2": "string",
          "opt3": "Float",
          "opt4": "unsigned",
          "ans": "interface"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which is a legal array declarations?",
          "opt1": "int [/] myScores [/];",
          "opt2": "char [/] myChars;",
          "opt3": "Dog myDogs [/];",
          "opt4": "All are correct",
          "ans": "All are correct"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which is a valid declaration of a char?",
          "opt1": "char c1 = 064770;",
          "opt2": "char c2 = 'face';",
          "opt3": "char c3 = iface;",
          "opt4": "char c4 = u0022;",
          "ans": "char c1 = 064770;"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which is the valid declaration within an interface definition?",
          "opt1": "public double methoda();",
          "opt2": "public final double methoda();",
          "opt3": "static void methoda(double d1);",
          "opt4": "protected void methoda(double d1);",
          "ans": "public double methoda();"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which is a valid declaration of a boolean?",
          "opt1": "boolean b1 = 0;",
          "opt2": "boolean b2 = 'false';",
          "opt3": "boolean b3 = false;",
          "opt4": "boolean b4 = no;",
          "ans": "boolean b3 = false;"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the numerical range of a char?",
          "opt1": "-128 to 127",
          "opt2": "-(215) to (215) - 1",
          "opt3": "0 to 32767",
          "opt4": "0 to 65535",
          "ans": "0 to 65535"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the prototype of the default constructor?",
          "opt1": "Test( )",
          "opt2": "Test(void)",
          "opt3": "public Test( )",
          "opt4": "public Test(void)",
          "ans": "public Test( )"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which gives access to members of another class in the same package?",
          "opt1": "public",
          "opt2": "private",
          "opt3": "protected",
          "opt4": "default access",
          "ans": "default access"
        }
      ]
    }, {
      "Apprentice": [
        {
          "question": "Which class does not override the equals() and hashCode() methods?",
          "opt1": "java.lang.String",
          "opt2": "java.lang.Double",
          "opt3": "java.lang.StringBuffer",
          "opt4": "java.lang.Character",
          "ans": "java.lang.StringBuffer"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which interface does java.util.Hashtable implement?",
          "opt1": "Java.util.Map",
          "opt2": "Java.util.List",
          "opt3": "Java.util.HashTable",
          "opt4": "Java.util.Collection",
          "ans": "Java.util.Map"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which interface provides the capability to store objects using a key-value pair?",
          "opt1": "Java.util.Map",
          "opt2": "Java.util.Set",
          "opt3": "Java.util.List",
          "opt4": "Java.util.Collection",
          "ans": "Java.util.Map"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which is valid declaration of a float?",
          "opt1": "float f = 1.0;",
          "opt2": "float f = 1F;",
          "opt3": "float f = \"1\";",
          "opt4": "float f = 1.0d;",
          "ans": "float f = 1F;"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the numerical range of char?",
          "opt1": "0 to 32767",
          "opt2": "0 to 65535",
          "opt3": "-256 to 255",
          "opt4": "-32768 to 32767",
          "ans": "0 to 65535"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following are Java reserved words?",
          "opt1": "run",
          "opt2": "import",
          "opt3": "implement",
          "opt4": "extend",
          "ans": "import"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which statement is true for the class java.util.HashSet?",
          "opt1": "Its elements are ordered",
          "opt2": "Its guaranteed to be immutable",
          "opt3": "Its elements are guaranteed to be unique",
          "opt4": "Its elements are accessed using a unique key",
          "ans": "Its elements are guaranteed to be unique"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following statements about the hashcode() method are incorrect?",
          "opt1": "The value returned is used to help locate objects",
          "opt2": "It is required to return a positive int value",
          "opt3": "Two new empty Strings produce same hashcodes",
          "opt4": "It is not inherited from Object",
          "ans": "It is required to return a positive int value"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which statement is true for the class java.util.ArrayList?",
          "opt1": "The elements are ordered",
          "opt2": "It is guaranteed to be immutable",
          "opt3": "The elements are unique",
          "opt4": "The elements are accessed using a unique key",
          "ans": "The elements are ordered"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following is true about ListIterator?",
          "opt1": "It can determine its position in the List",
          "opt2": "It enables forward and backward iteration",
          "opt3": "It can modify the List during iteration",
          "opt4": "All of the above",
          "ans": "All of the above"
        }
      ]
    }, {
      "Pro": [
        {
          "question": "Which is true about an anonymous inner class?",
          "opt1": "It can extend multiple classes",
          "opt2": "It can implement multiple interfaces",
          "opt3": "It can extend exactly one class",
          "opt4": "None of the above",
          "ans": "It can extend exactly one class"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which is true about a method-local inner class?",
          "opt1": "It must be marked final",
          "opt2": "It can be marked abstract",
          "opt3": "It can be marked public",
          "opt4": "It can be marked static",
          "ans": "It can be marked abstract"
        },
        {
          "question": "correct syntax for anonymous inner class instance?",
          "opt1": "new Runnable() { };",
          "opt2": "new Runnable(public void run(){});",
          "opt3": "new Runnable{public void run(){}};",
          "opt4": "All of the above",
          "ans": "new Runnable{public void run(){}};"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which method starts a thread execution?",
          "opt1": "init();",
          "opt2": "start();",
          "opt3": "run();",
          "opt4": "resume();",
          "ans": "start();"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which statement is true?",
          "opt1": "The Error class is a RuntimeException",
          "opt2": "catch(X x) can catch subclasses of X",
          "opt3": "try block is only used for Errors",
          "opt4": "catch block can catch all the errors",
          "ans": "catch(X x) can catch subclasses of X"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which is valid constructor for Thread?",
          "opt1": "Thread(Runnable r, String name)",
          "opt2": "Thread(Runnable r, int priority)",
          "opt3": "Thread(int priority)",
          "opt4": "Thread(Runnable r, ThreadGroup g)",
          "ans": "Thread(Runnable r, String name)"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which is the method of the Object class?",
          "opt1": "isInterrupted();",
          "opt2": "notify();",
          "opt3": "synchronized();",
          "opt4": "sleep(long msecs);",
          "ans": "notify();"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which method is defined in class Thread?",
          "opt1": "start()",
          "opt2": "wait()",
          "opt3": "notify()",
          "opt4": "terminate()",
          "ans": "start()"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which guarantees that a thread will leave the running state?",
          "opt1": "yield()",
          "opt2": "notify()",
          "opt3": "notifyAll()",
          "opt4": "sleep(1000)",
          "ans": "sleep(1000)"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which will directly stop the execution of a Thread?",
          "opt1": "notify()",
          "opt2": "notifyall()",
          "opt3": "wait()",
          "opt4": "exits synchronized code",
          "ans": "wait()"
        }
      ]
    }, {
      "Hitman": [
        {
          "question": "The throw statement can throw?",
          "opt1": "Event",
          "opt2": "Object",
          "opt3": "Error",
          "opt4": "None",
          "ans": "Error"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which will contain the body of the thread?",
          "opt1": "run();",
          "opt2": "start();",
          "opt3": "main();",
          "opt4": "stop();",
          "ans": "run();"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which method registers a thread in a thread scheduler?",
          "opt1": "construct();",
          "opt2": "run();",
          "opt3": "start();",
          "opt4": "register();",
          "ans": "start();"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following will not directly cause a thread to stop?",
          "opt1": "notify()",
          "opt2": "wait()",
          "opt3": "sleep()",
          "opt4": "InputStream access",
          "ans": "notify()"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following would compile without error?",
          "opt1": "int a = Math.abs(-5);",
          "opt2": "int b = Math.abs(5.0);",
          "opt3": "int c = Math.abs(5.5F);",
          "opt4": "int d = Math.abs(5L);",
          "ans": "int a = Math.abs(-5);"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following is valid call to Math.max?",
          "opt1": "Math.max(1,4)",
          "opt2": "Math.max(2.3, 5)",
          "opt3": "Math.max(-1.5, -2.8f)",
          "opt4": "All of the above",
          "ans": "All of the above"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which will produce an answer closest in value to a double, d, while not being greater than d?",
          "opt1": "(int)Math.min(d);",
          "opt2": "(int)Math.max(d);",
          "opt3": "(int)Math.abs(d);",
          "opt4": "(int)Math.floor(d);",
          "ans": "(int)Math.floor(d);"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which is true about the result obtained from calling Math.random()?",
          "opt1": "result is less than 0.0",
          "opt2": "The result is less than 1.0",
          "opt3": "The result is greater than 1.0",
          "opt4": "The result is equal to 1.0",
          "ans": "The result is less than 1.0"
        },
        {
          "question": "which of these will create and start a thread?",
          "opt1": "new Runnable(MyRunnable).start();",
          "opt2": "new Thread(MyRunnable).run();",
          "opt3": "new Thread(new MyRunnable()).start();",
          "opt4": "new MyRunnable().start();",
          "ans": "new Thread(new MyRunnable()).start();"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which classinterface defines the wait(), notify(),and notifyAll() methods?",
          "opt1": "Object",
          "opt2": "Thread",
          "opt3": "Runnable",
          "opt4": "Class",
          "ans": "Object"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "iOS": [
    {
      "Rookie": [
        {
          "question": "iOS was first released in?",
          "opt1": "2008",
          "opt2": "2005",
          "opt3": "2006",
          "opt4": "2007",
          "ans": "2007"
        },
        {
          "question": "What type of software is iOS?",
          "opt1": "Proprietary",
          "opt2": "Open-source",
          "opt3": "Secret",
          "opt4": "None of these",
          "ans": "Proprietary"
        },
        {
          "question": "Most popular mobile operating system with highest market share in the world?",
          "opt1": "iOS",
          "opt2": "Android",
          "opt3": "Windows Phone",
          "opt4": "Java ME",
          "ans": "Android"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which one of these devices does not run on iOS?",
          "opt1": "iPhone",
          "opt2": "iPad",
          "opt3": "iPod",
          "opt4": "iSee",
          "ans": "iSee"
        },
        {
          "question": "The system belongs to which OS family?",
          "opt1": "Windows NT",
          "opt2": "Darwin",
          "opt3": "Linux",
          "opt4": "QNX",
          "ans": "Darwin"
        },
        {
          "question": "Multitasking for iOS was first released in which year?",
          "opt1": "2010",
          "opt2": "2008",
          "opt3": "2012",
          "opt4": "2011",
          "ans": "2010"
        },
        {
          "question": "What was the original name of iOS?",
          "opt1": "iPad OS",
          "opt2": "iPhone OS",
          "opt3": "iPod OS",
          "opt4": "iOS is the original name",
          "ans": "iPhone OS"
        },
        {
          "question": "Who has the largest market share for tablets worldwide?",
          "opt1": "iOS",
          "opt2": "Android",
          "opt3": "Kindle",
          "opt4": "None",
          "ans": "iOS"
        },
        {
          "question": "iOS is a mobile operating system developed by",
          "opt1": "LG",
          "opt2": "Siemens",
          "opt3": "Apple Inc.",
          "opt4": "Samsung",
          "ans": "Apple Inc."
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the official application store of iOS?",
          "opt1": "Apple Play",
          "opt2": "App Store",
          "opt3": "Jolla Store",
          "opt4": "Play Store",
          "ans": "App Store"
        }
      ]
    }, {
      "Apprentice": [
        {
          "question": "Which keyword do you use to declare enumeration?",
          "opt1": "var",
          "opt2": "let",
          "opt3": "enum",
          "opt4": "e(num)",
          "ans": "enum"
        },
        {
          "question": "A class that's defined solely so that other classes can inherit from it?",
          "opt1": "Anonymous object",
          "opt2": "Abstract class",
          "opt3": "ARC",
          "opt4": "Binary",
          "ans": "Abstract class"
        },
        {
          "question": "An object of unknown class. Interface is published through protocol declaration?",
          "opt1": "Protocols",
          "opt2": "Unsigned",
          "opt3": "Anonymous Object",
          "opt4": "Reciever",
          "ans": "Anonymous Object"
        },
        {
          "question": "_____ allows you to add new methods to existing classes",
          "opt1": "Categories",
          "opt2": "Dangling Pointer",
          "opt3": "Factory",
          "opt4": "Memory Leak",
          "ans": "Categories"
        },
        {
          "question": "______ operators take a single operand",
          "opt1": "Long long",
          "opt2": "Framework",
          "opt3": "Unitary",
          "opt4": "Enumerations",
          "ans": "Unitary"
        },
        {
          "question": "Same as class object. (first way to say it.)",
          "opt1": "factory",
          "opt2": "double",
          "opt3": "assign",
          "opt4": "mutex",
          "ans": "factory"
        },
        {
          "question": "An object id with a value of 0?",
          "opt1": "C Operators",
          "opt2": "Developer intent",
          "opt3": "nil",
          "opt4": "[reciever message];",
          "ans": "nil"
        },
        {
          "question": "A _______ method is one that is likely to be unsupported in the future.",
          "opt1": "Categories",
          "opt2": "deprecated",
          "opt3": "delegate",
          "opt4": "Enumerations",
          "ans": "deprecated"
        },
        {
          "question": "A ____ ____ is where you free memory and then accidentally continue to use it.",
          "opt1": "dangling pointer",
          "opt2": "Unsigned",
          "opt3": "procedural language",
          "opt4": "nonatomic",
          "ans": "dangling pointer"
        },
        {
          "question": "A set of method definitions that is segregated from the rest of the class definition?",
          "opt1": "instance",
          "opt2": "category",
          "opt3": "Unsigned",
          "opt4": "protocol",
          "ans": "category"
        }
      ]
    }, {
      "Pro": [
        {
          "question": "There are ____ fundamental building blocks in Objective-C.",
          "opt1": "10",
          "opt2": "9",
          "opt3": "8",
          "opt4": "6",
          "ans": "9"
        },
        {
          "question": "A method that can operate on class objects rather than instances of the class",
          "opt1": "instance",
          "opt2": "class method",
          "opt3": "zero",
          "opt4": "%",
          "ans": "class method"
        },
        {
          "question": "The mathematical concept of 'order of operations' is known as the 'order of ______?",
          "opt1": "Superset",
          "opt2": "C operators",
          "opt3": "precedence",
          "opt4": "Categories",
          "ans": "precedence"
        },
        {
          "question": "____ provide a concise & elegant method for defining a discrete set of values.",
          "opt1": "inheritance",
          "opt2": "Enumerations",
          "opt3": "informal protocol",
          "opt4": "Interface Builder",
          "ans": "Enumerations"
        },
        {
          "question": "Placing a ____ before a normal variable name gives it's address.",
          "opt1": "selector",
          "opt2": "abstract superclass",
          "opt3": "class object",
          "opt4": "ampersand (&)",
          "ans": ""
        },
        {
          "question": "Correct syntax for calling a method?",
          "opt1": "delegates",
          "opt2": "[receiver message];",
          "opt3": "@interface",
          "opt4": "dynamic binding",
          "ans": "[receiver message];"
        },
        {
          "question": "A ____ _____ is where you forget to free up memory.",
          "opt1": "designation",
          "opt2": "pointer",
          "opt3": "memory leak",
          "opt4": "exception",
          "ans": "memory leak"
        },
        {
          "question": "The most flexible C data type: ______.",
          "opt1": "pointers",
          "opt2": "struct",
          "opt3": "enum",
          "opt4": "None of the above",
          "ans": "struct"
        },
        {
          "question": "Objective-C is a _____ of the C language.",
          "opt1": "id",
          "opt2": "attribute",
          "opt3": "subset",
          "opt4": "superset",
          "ans": "superset"
        },
        {
          "question": "The process of setting or reading the value at an address pointed to by a pointer.",
          "opt1": "dereferencing",
          "opt2": "pointing",
          "opt3": "unitary",
          "opt4": "locating",
          "ans": "dereferencing"
        }
      ]
    }, {
      "Hitman": [
        {
          "question": "A logical subdivision of a program within which all names must be unique.",
          "opt1": "remote message",
          "opt2": "comma-separated",
          "opt3": "namespace",
          "opt4": "square brackets",
          "ans": "namespace"
        },
        {
          "question": "A class is said to do this when it declares that it implements all the methods in the protocol.",
          "opt1": "framework",
          "opt2": "cast",
          "opt3": "adopt",
          "opt4": "build",
          "ans": "adopt"
        },
        {
          "question": "Objective-C binds methods and arguments at _____ instead of compile time.",
          "opt1": "run time",
          "opt2": "compile time",
          "opt3": "interfaces",
          "opt4": "None",
          "ans": "compile time"
        },
        {
          "question": "Objective-C methods are called using ____ _____.",
          "opt1": "NS String",
          "opt2": "static typing",
          "opt3": "designated",
          "opt4": "square brackets",
          "ans": "square brackets"
        },
        {
          "question": "A message sent from one application to an object in another application.",
          "opt1": "package",
          "opt2": "Smalltalk",
          "opt3": "remote message",
          "opt4": "quanta",
          "ans": ""
        },
        {
          "question": "A compiler feature that provides automated memory management.",
          "opt1": "ARC",
          "opt2": "superset",
          "opt3": "delegates",
          "opt4": "NSString",
          "ans": "ARC"
        },
        {
          "question": "C-style strings are stored in an array of _____.",
          "opt1": "integers",
          "opt2": "chars",
          "opt3": "strings",
          "opt4": "objects",
          "ans": "chars"
        },
        {
          "question": "Property attribute that causes the setter to store a zeroing weak reference.",
          "opt1": "Encapsulation",
          "opt2": "doubles",
          "opt3": "weak",
          "opt4": "cycles",
          "ans": "weak"
        },
        {
          "question": "The root class in Objective-C.",
          "opt1": "Object",
          "opt2": "NSObject",
          "opt3": "Dispach",
          "opt4": "CObject",
          "ans": "NSObject"
        },
        {
          "question": "Property attribute that synthesizes accessors that are not thread safe.",
          "opt1": "pointers",
          "opt2": "nonatomic",
          "opt3": "doubles",
          "opt4": "cycles",
          "ans": "nonatomic"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "HTML": [
    {
      "Rookie": [
        {
          "question": "Which tag is used for line break in HTML?",
          "opt1": "bl",
          "opt2": "lb",
          "opt3": "bk",
          "opt4": "br",
          "ans": "br"
        },
        {
          "question": "HTML stands for:",
          "opt1": "Heavy Text Markup Language",
          "opt2": "Hyper Text Markup Language",
          "opt3": "Hyper Text Marking Language",
          "opt4": "Hyber Text Markup Language",
          "ans": "Hyper Text Markup Language"
        },
        {
          "question": "The title tag is given in?",
          "opt1": "Footer",
          "opt2": "Head",
          "opt3": "Body",
          "opt4": "Paragraph",
          "ans": "Head"
        },
        {
          "question": "The space between the table data value and its border is called?",
          "opt1": "Cell shaping",
          "opt2": "Cell spacing",
          "opt3": "Cell framing",
          "opt4": "Cell padding",
          "ans": "Cell padding"
        },
        {
          "question": "HTML documents are having extension?",
          "opt1": "code",
          "opt2": "html",
          "opt3": "doc",
          "opt4": "web",
          "ans": "html"
        },
        {
          "question": "What are the different levels of headings in HTML?",
          "opt1": "1-3",
          "opt2": "1-5",
          "opt3": "1-4",
          "opt4": "1-6",
          "ans": "1-6"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following is a bulleted list?",
          "opt1": "OI",
          "opt2": "BI",
          "opt3": "UI",
          "opt4": "TI",
          "ans": "UI"
        },
        {
          "question": "The following tag is used to define a row in a table:",
          "opt1": "td",
          "opt2": "tr",
          "opt3": "table",
          "opt4": "tb",
          "ans": "tr"
        },
        {
          "question": "The following tag is used to define a paragraph:",
          "opt1": "par",
          "opt2": "p",
          "opt3": "Paragraph",
          "opt4": "None of these",
          "ans": "p"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which heading style is the biggest?",
          "opt1": "H",
          "opt2": "H6",
          "opt3": "H1",
          "opt4": "H5",
          "ans": "H1"
        }
      ]
    }, {
      "Apprentice": [
        {
          "question": "the correct HTML element to define important text:",
          "opt1": "<i>",
          "opt2": "<b>",
          "opt3": "<strong>",
          "opt4": "<important>",
          "ans": "<strong>"
        },
        {
          "question": "Choose the correct HTML element to define emphasized text:",
          "opt1": "<i>",
          "opt2": "<italic>",
          "opt3": "<em>",
          "opt4": "<e>",
          "ans": "<em>"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which character is used to indicate an end tag?",
          "opt1": "/",
          "opt2": "*",
          "opt3": ">",
          "opt4": "^",
          "ans": "/"
        },
        {
          "question": "How can you open a link in a new tab/browser window?",
          "opt1": "target=\"new\"",
          "opt2": "target=\"_blank\"",
          "opt3": "\"url\" new",
          "opt4": "target=\"new tab\"",
          "ans": "target=\"_blank\""
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of these elements are all <table> elements?",
          "opt1": "<table><head><tfoot>",
          "opt2": "<thead><body><tr>",
          "opt3": "<table><tr><td>",
          "opt4": "<table><title><td>",
          "ans": "<table><tr><td>"
        },
        {
          "question": "Inline elements are normally displayed without starting a new line.",
          "opt1": "True",
          "opt2": "False",
          "opt3": "Not necessary",
          "opt4": "Maybe",
          "ans": "True"
        },
        {
          "question": "How can you make a numbered list?",
          "opt1": "<ol>",
          "opt2": "<ul>",
          "opt3": "<list>",
          "opt4": "<dl>",
          "ans": "<ol>"
        },
        {
          "question": "How can you make a bulleted list?",
          "opt1": "<dl>",
          "opt2": "<list>",
          "opt3": "<ol>",
          "opt4": "<ul>",
          "ans": "<ul>"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the correct HTML for making a checkbox?",
          "opt1": "<checkbox>",
          "opt2": "<input type=\"check\">",
          "opt3": "<check>",
          "opt4": "<input type=\"checkbox\">",
          "ans": "<input type=\"checkbox\">"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the correct HTML for making a text input field?",
          "opt1": "<textfield>",
          "opt2": "<textinput type=\"text\">",
          "opt3": "<input type=\"textfield\">",
          "opt4": "<input type=\"text\">",
          "ans": "<input type=\"text\">"
        }
      ]
    }, {
      "Pro": [
        {
          "question": "What is the correct HTML for making a drop-down list?",
          "opt1": "<input type=\"list\">",
          "opt2": "<select>",
          "opt3": "<input type=\"dropdown\">",
          "opt4": "<list>",
          "ans": "<input type=\"list\">"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the correct HTML for making a text area?",
          "opt1": "<input type=\"textarea\">",
          "opt2": "<textarea>",
          "opt3": "<input type=\"text\">",
          "opt4": "<input type=\"textbox\">",
          "ans": ""
        },
        {
          "question": "An <iframe> is used to display a web page within a web page.",
          "opt1": "False",
          "opt2": "True",
          "opt3": "<iframe> is nothing",
          "opt4": "Maybe",
          "ans": "True"
        },
        {
          "question": "HTML comments start with <!-- and end with -->",
          "opt1": "True",
          "opt2": "False",
          "opt3": "Maybe",
          "opt4": "Not necessary",
          "ans": "True"
        },
        {
          "question": "Block elements are normally displayed without starting a new line.",
          "opt1": "False",
          "opt2": "True",
          "opt3": "Maybe",
          "opt4": "Not necessary",
          "ans": "False"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which HTML element defines the title of a document?",
          "opt1": "<head>",
          "opt2": "<title>",
          "opt3": "<meta>",
          "opt4": "<body>",
          "ans": "<title>"
        },
        {
          "question": "Standard attributes specified when defining a FRAME?",
          "opt1": "SRC and NAME",
          "opt2": "SRC, NAME, and ROW",
          "opt3": "NAME and FRAMESET",
          "opt4": "BODY, SRC, and TITLE",
          "ans": "NAME and FRAMESET"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following is not an attribute of the FRAME tag?",
          "opt1": "SCROLLING",
          "opt2": "AUTO",
          "opt3": "MARGINWIDTH",
          "opt4": "FRAMEBORDER",
          "ans": "MARGINWIDTH"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following is not a valid attribute of the INPUT tag?",
          "opt1": "TEXT",
          "opt2": "NAME",
          "opt3": "SIZE",
          "opt4": "MAXLENGTH",
          "ans": "TEXT"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which tag is most suited for laying out a FORM?",
          "opt1": "TEXT",
          "opt2": "POST",
          "opt3": "PRE",
          "opt4": "PREFORMAT",
          "ans": "PREFORMAT"
        }
      ]
    }, {
      "Hitman": [
        {
          "question": "Tags and test that are not directly displayed on the page are written in _____ section.",
          "opt1": "<html>",
          "opt2": "<head>",
          "opt3": "<title>",
          "opt4": "<body>",
          "ans": "<head>"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which tag inserts a line horizontally on your web page?",
          "opt1": "<hr>",
          "opt2": "<line>",
          "opt3": "<tr>",
          "opt4": "<line direction=ï¿½horizontalï¿½>",
          "ans": "<hr>"
        },
        {
          "question": "What does vlink attribute mean?",
          "opt1": "visited link",
          "opt2": "virtual link",
          "opt3": "very good link",
          "opt4": "active link",
          "ans": "visited link"
        },
        {
          "question": "To create a combo box (drop down box) which tag will you use?",
          "opt1": "<select>",
          "opt2": "<list>",
          "opt3": "<input type=ï¿½dropdownï¿½>",
          "opt4": "all of above",
          "ans": "<select>"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following is not a pair tag?",
          "opt1": "<p>",
          "opt2": "<u>",
          "opt3": "<i>",
          "opt4": "<img>",
          "ans": "<img>"
        },
        {
          "question": "Some tags enclose the text. Those tags are known as:",
          "opt1": "Couple tags",
          "opt2": "Single tags",
          "opt3": "Double tags",
          "opt4": "Pair tags",
          "ans": "Pair tags"
        },
        {
          "question": "The _____ character tells browsers to stop tagging the text:",
          "opt1": "?",
          "opt2": "/",
          "opt3": ">",
          "opt4": "%",
          "ans": ""
        },
        {
          "question": "There are ____ different of heading tags in HTML.",
          "opt1": "4",
          "opt2": "5",
          "opt3": "6",
          "opt4": "8",
          "ans": "6"
        },
        {
          "question": "Text within <EM> ï¿½ </EM> tag is displayed as:",
          "opt1": "bold",
          "opt2": "italic",
          "opt3": "list",
          "opt4": "indented",
          "ans": "italic"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which HTML tag would be used to display power in expression (A+B)2 ?",
          "opt1": "<P>",
          "opt2": "<SUP>",
          "opt3": "<SUB>",
          "opt4": "<B>",
          "ans": "<SUP>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "JavaScript": [
    {
      "Rookie": [
        {
          "question": "Javascript is __ language.",
          "opt1": "Client Side",
          "opt2": "Server Side",
          "opt3": "Both",
          "opt4": "None",
          "ans": "Client Side"
        },
        {
          "question": "The browser uses __ tag to detect javascript.",
          "opt1": "<js></js>",
          "opt2": "<script type=\"text/javascript\"/>",
          "opt3": "<scripting></scripting>",
          "opt4": "<javascript></javascript>",
          "ans": "<script type=\"text/javascript\"/>"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the alternate name for Java script?",
          "opt1": "LimeScript",
          "opt2": "Coffee Script",
          "opt3": "ECMScript",
          "opt4": "ECMAScript",
          "ans": "ECMAScript"
        },
        {
          "question": "JavaScript variables are case-sensitive.",
          "opt1": "True",
          "opt2": "False",
          "opt3": "Maybe",
          "opt4": "Maybe not",
          "ans": "True"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following is not a valid JavaScript variable name?",
          "opt1": "5myvalue",
          "opt2": "myvalue",
          "opt3": "myvalue5",
          "opt4": "None of the above",
          "ans": "5myvalue"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the output of this expression? x = 2 + \"2\"; document.write(x);",
          "opt1": "22",
          "opt2": "2",
          "opt3": "4",
          "opt4": "Syntax Error",
          "ans": "22"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which is the correct order of precedence of Arithmetic operators?",
          "opt1": "+/*-",
          "opt2": "+-*/",
          "opt3": "*/+-",
          "opt4": "+*-/",
          "ans": "*/+-"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the output of this strict equality operator? 5 === \"5\"?",
          "opt1": "True",
          "opt2": "False",
          "opt3": "Maybe",
          "opt4": "Maybe not",
          "ans": "False"
        },
        {
          "question": "The __ operator determines the type of a given object.",
          "opt1": "typeof",
          "opt2": "void",
          "opt3": "instanceof",
          "opt4": "delete",
          "ans": "typeof"
        },
        {
          "question": "The __ operator determines whether an object is an instance of another object.",
          "opt1": "typeof",
          "opt2": "void",
          "opt3": "instanceof",
          "opt4": "delete",
          "ans": "instanceof"
        }
      ]
    }, {
      "Apprentice": [
        {
          "question": "Javascript is __ language.",
          "opt1": "Loosely Typed",
          "opt2": "Strongly Typed",
          "opt3": "Dynamic",
          "opt4": "Loosely Typed & Dynamic",
          "ans": ""
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following is a JavaScript datatype?",
          "opt1": "Null",
          "opt2": "Object",
          "opt3": "Undefined",
          "opt4": "All of them",
          "ans": "All of them"
        },
        {
          "question": "typeof NaN (Not a Number)?",
          "opt1": "Number",
          "opt2": "String",
          "opt3": "NaN",
          "opt4": "Object",
          "ans": "Number"
        },
        {
          "question": "typeof null?",
          "opt1": "Number",
          "opt2": "String",
          "opt3": "NaN",
          "opt4": "Object",
          "ans": "Object"
        },
        {
          "question": "typeof Infinity?",
          "opt1": "Number",
          "opt2": "String",
          "opt3": "NaN",
          "opt4": "Object",
          "ans": "Number"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the output? x = 100 / \"Mango\";",
          "opt1": "null",
          "opt2": "undefined",
          "opt3": "NaN",
          "opt4": "Infinity",
          "ans": "NaN"
        },
        {
          "question": "What does pop() method of the array do?",
          "opt1": "removes the first element",
          "opt2": "removes the last element",
          "opt3": "adds element to the array at first position",
          "opt4": "adds element to the array at last position",
          "ans": "adds element to the array at last position"
        },
        {
          "question": "The __ method of an Array object adds and/or removes elements from an array.",
          "opt1": "Reverse",
          "opt2": "Shift",
          "opt3": "Slice",
          "opt4": "Splice",
          "ans": "Splice"
        },
        {
          "question": "__ returns true if a variable is an array, if not false.",
          "opt1": "Array.isArray()",
          "opt2": "Array.of()",
          "opt3": "Array.from()",
          "opt4": "Array.observe()",
          "ans": "Array.isArray()"
        },
        {
          "question": "typeof ([\\]), typeof (new Array())",
          "opt1": "'array', 'object'",
          "opt2": "'object', 'array'",
          "opt3": "'array' , 'array'",
          "opt4": "'object', 'object'",
          "ans": "'object', 'object'"
        }
      ]
    }, {
      "Pro": [
        {
          "question": "How do you create a new object in JavaScript?",
          "opt1": "var obj = {};",
          "opt2": "var obj = Object();",
          "opt3": "var obj=new {};",
          "opt4": "None of the above",
          "ans": "var obj = {};"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following is a server-side JavaScript object?",
          "opt1": "FileUpLoad",
          "opt2": "Function",
          "opt3": "File",
          "opt4": "Date",
          "ans": "File"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the use of \"this\" keyword in javascript?",
          "opt1": "refers to current object",
          "opt2": "refers to previous object",
          "opt3": "variable which contains value",
          "opt4": "None of the above",
          "ans": "refers to current object"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following is a client-side JavaScript object?",
          "opt1": "Database",
          "opt2": "Cursor",
          "opt3": "Client",
          "opt4": "FileUpLoad",
          "ans": "FileUpLoad"
        },
        {
          "question": "How to add properties to object? var car = {};",
          "opt1": "car.make = \"Ford\";",
          "opt2": "car[\"make\"] = \"Ford\";",
          "opt3": "var car = {make: Ford};",
          "opt4": "All of the above",
          "ans": "All of the above"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which operator creates a new object from the specified object type?",
          "opt1": "obj",
          "opt2": "new",
          "opt3": "create",
          "opt4": "None of the above",
          "ans": "new"
        },
        {
          "question": "Is it valid to nest functions in JavaScript?",
          "opt1": "No",
          "opt2": "Yes",
          "opt3": "Maybe",
          "opt4": "Maybe not",
          "ans": "Yes"
        },
        {
          "question": "Function name becomes optional in JavaScript when it is...?",
          "opt1": "defined within function",
          "opt2": "defined using constructor",
          "opt3": "defined as an expression",
          "opt4": "predefined",
          "ans": "defined as an expression"
        },
        {
          "question": "Array-like object containing the arguments passed to currently executing function?",
          "opt1": "arguments",
          "opt2": "function",
          "opt3": "args",
          "opt4": "None of the above",
          "ans": "arguments"
        },
        {
          "question": "The missing parameters int the function get assigned the value __.",
          "opt1": "undefined",
          "opt2": "null",
          "opt3": "Syntax Error",
          "opt4": "None of the above",
          "ans": "undefined"
        }
      ]
    }, {
      "Hitman": [
        {
          "question": "__ statement is used to test for a specific condition.",
          "opt1": "Select",
          "opt2": "If",
          "opt3": "Switch",
          "opt4": "For",
          "ans": "If"
        },
        {
          "question": "What are the looping structures are available in javascripts?",
          "opt1": "for, foreach",
          "opt2": "foreach, while",
          "opt3": "do-while, foreach",
          "opt4": "for, while, do-while",
          "ans": "for, while, do-while"
        },
        {
          "question": "isNaN function returns _____ if the argument is not a number.",
          "opt1": "true",
          "opt2": "false",
          "opt3": "null",
          "opt4": "undefined",
          "ans": "true"
        },
        {
          "question": "__ statement breaks the loop and executes the code after the loop.",
          "opt1": "continue",
          "opt2": "break",
          "opt3": "return",
          "opt4": "goto",
          "ans": "break"
        },
        {
          "question": "parseFloat(\"9.9Hello\")?",
          "opt1": "9",
          "opt2": "9.9",
          "opt3": "99",
          "opt4": "9.9Hello",
          "ans": "9.9"
        },
        {
          "question": "__ returns the milliseconds in a date string.",
          "opt1": "getTime()",
          "opt2": "Date.UTC()",
          "opt3": "Date.parse()",
          "opt4": "None of the above",
          "ans": "Date.parse()"
        },
        {
          "question": "The JavaScript __ class represents regular expressions.",
          "opt1": "RegExpObj",
          "opt2": "RegExpClass",
          "opt3": "RegExp",
          "opt4": "StringExp",
          "ans": "RegExp"
        },
        {
          "question": "How to test the pattern for a given text?",
          "opt1": "text==pattern",
          "opt2": "text.equals(pattern)",
          "opt3": "text.test(pattern)",
          "opt4": "pattern.test(text)",
          "ans": "pattern.test(text)"
        },
        {
          "question": "eval(20*4)=?",
          "opt1": "NaN",
          "opt2": "204",
          "opt3": "24",
          "opt4": "80",
          "ans": "80"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which are the ways to enumerate all properties of an object?",
          "opt1": "for...in loops",
          "opt2": "Object.keys()",
          "opt3": "Object.getOwnPropertyNames()",
          "opt4": "All of the above",
          "ans": "All of the above"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}